# Pieter Montoulieu

#### **README**

Hey there, my name is Pieter Montoulieu and I'm a game developer and full stack engineer living in Denver, Colorado. I'm currently specializing in XR with Unity and React/JAMstack web applications.

I've been developing video games and web apps since 2000, and have loved getting to work with the many technologies that have evolved since then.

When I'm not coding, I'm recording something new in my studio or playing a show in the local Denver music scene.

While I'm a jack of many trades, I feel I've mastered some over the last 15 years, and that my passion for video games and modern web design principles gives me the drive to make anything possible.

## **GAMEDEV SKILLS**

#### Unity

- C# (8+ years)
- SteamVR/OVR/XR Interaction/HurricaneVR
- Shader Graph
- URP/HDRP
- Probuilder
- Audio Mixer
- Physics (Rigidbodies, Joints, etc)
- U1
- SCM / Collab

#### 3D / Graphics

- Blender
- Maya
- Photoshop
- Figma

# Audio / Video

- Sound Effect Design
- Chiptune / Retro Video Game Music
- Orchestral Composition
- Logic / Ableton 10
- Davinci Resolve / Final Cut Pro

# **WEBDEV SKILLS**

# React / React Native

- Next.js
- Gatsby
- Expo
- State Management (Redux, MobX, Flux, Zustand, xState, Context)
- Styled Components

# **Javascript**

- ES9
- Node / Express
- Serverless and LAMBDA functions
- Webpack / PostCSS

# PHP

- Laravel
- Wordpress
- Apache/Nginx

## UI

- Tailwind, Bootstrap, Material UI, Foundation
- Storybook

#### DB

- GraphQL
- MySQL / PostgreSQL

## **Deployment**

- Git and version control
- Netlify, Vercel
- DigitalOcean
- AWS, Azure

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Montoulieu Corp, Denver - CEO, Lead Engineer

#### NOV 2019 - PRESENT

Montoulieu Corp is the game and web development company that I started. We've worked with local clients like Colorado Film School and have built out XR concepts and prototypes over the last year.

# Spire Digital, Denver - Full Stack Engineer

#### DEC 2018 - PRESENT

Spire Digital is an agency with awesome leadership and work culture, which has led to some great client relationships.

During my time here I've been able to build a customer facing React SPA for WOW Internet Communications and an internal SPA for RE/MAX, which is used nationally by their agents to automate video and image ads for all their housing listings.

# **Graphik Creative, Denver** - Full Stack Engineer

#### NOV 2015 - OCT 2018

Graphik was a great company to work with, I got to lead a dev team on internal React and Laravel applications for DaVita, Vail Resorts and other local Colorado companies as well as hone my eye for design and typography.

# Orange Collar Media, Location — Frontend Developer

#### FEB 2014 - OCT 2015

My time at Orange Collar Media was a great learning experience for working with multiple clients and learning more PHP and Magento. During my time there I built several storefronts for national and local Colorado businesses.

# **EDUCATION**

#### Barron Collier High School, Naples, FL

May 2003 - May 2007, Naples, FL